A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev Bronk, Personal and Professional papers FA965
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev Bronk, Personal and Professional papers
1897-1978; Bulk: 1940-1975
1940-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Bronk, Detlev W. (Detlev Wulf), 1897-1975
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Rockefeller University
FA965
188.4 Cubic Feet 157 record storage cartons. Extent is approximate.
157 record storage cartons.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 303-U
Arrangement
The Bronk personal and professional papers are arranged partially chronologically, and partially by subject.
Related Materials
See also: FA220 Rockefeller University records, Executive Assistant, Mabel Bright.
Mabel Bright served as executive assistant to Detlev W. Bronk at Rockefeller University.
Scope and Contents
Includes administrative files; Bronk family history; organizational (national and International) activities; personal and professional correspondence; published clippings; research notes, papers, printed material, photos, graphs; speaking engagements.
The majority of the collection concerns Bronk's personal and professional papers as he served as:
1. 1921-1929 Asst. Prof., Assoc. Prof., Professor, Dean of Men, Swarthmore College.
2. 1929-1948 Professor of Biophysics and Director of the Eldridge Reeves Johnson Foundation for Medical Physics at the University of Pennsylvania.
3. 1936-1948 Director, Institute of Neurology at the University of Pennsylvania.
4. 1940-1941 Professor of Physiology at the Medical College of Cornell University.
5. 1948-1953 President of Johns Hopkins University.
6. 1952 President, American Association for Advancement of Science.
7. 1953-1969 President of the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (The Rockefeller University).
8. 1950-1962 President of The National Academy of Sciences.
In addition to work performed in these major administrative positions, the Bronk Papers contain files that were created as Bronk served on a host of national and international scientific organizations such as The National Science Foundation, National Research Council, Office of Scientific Research and Development, New York State Science and Technology Foundation, UNESCO, The Royal Society, International Council of Scientific Unions, and the Organization of American States.
Published articles, lectures and personal notes show the wide scope of Bronk's research activities. Addresses and records of speaking engagements evince Bronk's reach into the academic and scientific world community.
3.5 cubic feet of published clippings have been photocopied for research usage. Includes memorabilia such as awards, medals and honorary degrees. Family genealogies and histories enlarge understanding of Bronk's personal orientation.
During World War II Bronk was appointed Coordinator of Research, Office of the Air Surgeon, U.S. Army Air Forces (1942-1946). Numerous files show Bronk's interest and contributions to aviation medicine.
The collection contains many published and unpublished manuscripts Bronk received as editor of various publications, i.e. American Journal of Physiology (1938-1943), Aviation Physiologists Bulletin (1943-1946), Journal of General Physiology (1954-1968).
Bronk was appointed a member of the Advisory Committee to President Dwight D. Eisenhower on Science and Space. In 1958, as President of The National Academy of Science, he organized the Space Science Board, a board designated to study future space vehicles. Records and research studies of projected space programs are found in the files.
The Bronk Papers demonstrate Bronk's extensive acquaintance, friendship and scientific work with scientists and educators. A sampling of correspondents include E.D. Adrian, Frank Brink, Leslie A. Chambers, Britton Chance, H.K. Hartline, E. Newton Hervey, A.V. Hill, M.G. Larrabee, Glenn Millikan, and Arthur J. Rawson.
Other Finding Aids
FA140 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, Administrative papers.
FA914 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, General and Professional correspondence.
FA964 Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk, Biographical and Personal material.
Arrangement
The Rockefeller University records, President, Detlev W. Bronk materials are arranged into 4 components:
Administrative papers (FA140)
General and Professional correspondence (FA914)
Biographical and Personal Material (FA964)
Personal and Professional papers (FA965)
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 48 business hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those that are not available in modern formats, may require creation of an access surrogate. Applicable charges will apply.
Aviation medicine; Biology -- Research; Medical research; Operations management; Physiology; Medical sciences
- Personal and professional papers
  - 1940s War Work, AAF School of Aviation Medicine (AAFSAM), 1942-1946 (Box 1)
    - Army Air Force School of Aviation Medicine (AAFSAM), 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 January-February (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 April-June (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 July (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 August (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 September (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 October (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 November (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 November (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - AAFSAM, 1944 December (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 January (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 January (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 February (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 March (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 April (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 May (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 June (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 July (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 August (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 September (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 October (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 November (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - AAFSAM, 1945 December (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - AAFSAM, 1946 January (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - AAFSAM, 1946 February (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - AAFSAM, 1946 March-April (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - AAFSAM, 1946 May-June (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - AAFSAM, Naval Medical Research Institute (NMRI), Office of Research and Development (OSRD), 1941-1945
    - Army Air Force School of Aviation Medicine (AAFSAM), Naval Medical 1, 1945 April-August (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - AAFSAM, NMRI, Medical Field Research Laboratory, 1945 March-April (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - AAFSAM, NMRI, Medical Field Research Laboratory, 1945 May-July (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - AAFSAM, NMRI, 1944 November-1945 September (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - AAFSAM, NMRI, 1944 August-1945 September (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - AAFSAM, NMRI, 1944 October-1945 September (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - National Research Council (NRC), 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - NRC, Office of Research and Development (OSRD), 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bibliography of Visual Literature, 1939-1944 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bibliography of Visual Literature, Supplement, 1939-1944 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - F. Brink, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - F. Brink, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - NRC, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Medical Research Council, NRC, Subcommittee on Clinical Research, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Subcommittee On Clinical Research, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - OSRD, Subcommittee on Clinical Research, NRC, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - OSRD, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Aviation Physiologists, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - OSRD, NRD, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - OSRD, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - OSRD, Miscellaneous Reports on Clothing and Physiology of Cold, 1941-1943 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - OSRD, Miscellaneous Reports on Clothing and Physiology of Cold, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - OSRD, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - OSRD, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Elgin Field, Florida, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Elgin Field, Florida, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - OSRD, National Research Council (NRC), Aviation Medicine, NMRI, 1941-1946
    - Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD), 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Federal Security Agency (FDA), Studies in Aviation Medicine, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - FDA, Studies in Aviation Medicine, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - FDA, Studies in Aviation Medicine, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - FDA, Studies in Aviation Medicine, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Medical Research Council, Miscellaneous Reports on Night Vision, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - NRC, FDA, 1941-1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Medical Research Council, Miscellaneous Reports for the Armored Force, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Reports on Sensory Devices, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - NRC, Medical Research Council, Flying Personnel Research Committee, 1941-1944 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Flying Personnel Research Committee, Aviation Medical Research, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Naval Medical Research Institute (NMRI), Naval School of Aviation Medicine (NSAM), 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - NMRI, NSAM, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - NMRI, NSAM, 1944 March-August (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - NMRI, NSAM, 1944 October (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - NMRI, NSAM, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - NMRI, NSAM, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - NMRI, NSAM, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - NMRI, NSAM, Aviation Medicine-Miscellaneous, 1944 January-April (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - NMRI, NSAM, Aviation Medicine-Miscellaneous, 1944 May-October (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Aviation Medicine-Miscellaneous, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - NMRI, NSAM, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Aviation Medicine-Miscellaneous, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - NMRI, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Emergency Rescue Equipment, Aviation Medicine-Miscellaneous, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Aviation Medicine-Miscellaneous, Air Sea Rescue, NMRI, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - NMRI, NSAM, Aviation Medicine-Miscellaneous, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - NMRI, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - OSRD, NRC, AAFSAM, 1941-1944
    - Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD), 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - OSRD, National Research Council (NRC), 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - OSRD, Aviation Reports, Miscellaneous, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - OSRD, Army Air Force School of Aviation Medicine, Flying Personnel Research Committee, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - OSRD, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - NRC, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - NRC, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - OSRD, Aviation Medicine, Miscellaneous, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - NRC, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - NRC, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - OSRD, 1941 1943 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Naval Department - Bureau of Aeronautics, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - NRC, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - OSRD, 1941 August 28 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - NRC, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - NRC, 1943 March 4 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - NRC, Flying Personnel Research Committee, Army Air Force School of Aviation Medicine, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - NRC, Naval School of Aviation Medicine, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - NRC, 1941 August 7 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Army Air Force Materiel Command, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - NRC, Subcommittee on Oxygen and Anoxia, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - United States Public Health Service, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - NRC, British Air Commission, Army Air Force Headquarters, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - NRC, Bronk, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Army Air Force Materiel Command, 1943 August 14 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - NRC, Army Air Force Materiel Command, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - BRC, OSRD, 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - NRC, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - NRC, Flying Personnel Research Committee, 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - OSRD, 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - International Activities and Scientific Organizations, 1956-1975
    - International Foundation for Science (IFS), NRC, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - IFS, American Academy of Arts and Science, National Academy of 1, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - IFS, National Academy of Sciences, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - IFS, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - IFS, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - American Academy of Arts and Science, NRC, National Academy of Sciences, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - IFS, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - IFS, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Proposal for Establishment of an International University, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - The Club of Rome, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - The Club of Rome, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - The Club of Rome, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - The Club of Rome, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - World Academy of Arts and Science (WAAS), undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - WAAS, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - WAAS, 1961-1972 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - WAAS, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - WAAS, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - International Foundation for Science, Nobel and Rockefeller Foundations Workshop, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Institute of International Education, 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Institute for Advanced Scientific Study-Europe, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - International Association of Universities, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - International Cultural Foundation, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - International Institute of Science and Technology, 1962-1969 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - National Academy of Engineering, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - The Club of Rome, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - The Club of Rome, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - The Alpbach European Forum, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Nato Parliamentarians' Conference, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Pugwash Conferences, 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Pugwash Conferences, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - International Atomic Energy Study, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - National Defense Research Committee (NDRC), OSRD, Bronk Personal Papers, 1953-1979
    - Academy for Educational Development, 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - International University for Independent Study, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - American Academy of Arts and Science, 1963-1974 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - American Alpine Club, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - American Electroencephalographic Society, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Aerospace Medical Association, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1956-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - American Philosophical Society, Committee on Research, 1959-1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1960-1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - American Philosophical Society, Planning Commission on Liberty, 1965-1976 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1962-1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - American Society of Biological Chemists, 1954-1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Animal Medical Center, New York, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Aspen Institute of Humanistic Studies, 1958-1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Association of American Physicians, 1954-1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - American Foundation for Tropical Medicine, Liberian Institute, 1962-1966 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - American Hungarian Foundation, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - American Medical Association, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Aviation Commandery-Naval Order of the United States, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - The Brookings Institution, 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1966-1974 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Closed.
    - Canrad Precision Industries, Inc., 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Carnegie Institute of Washington, 1953-1956 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Center for Information on America, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Center for Inter-American Relations, Inc., 1969-1979 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1962-1975 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Pacem in Maribus (Elizabeth Mann Borgese), Conference on Caribbean and Gulf Development, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - City Club of New York - 80th Anniversary Dinner, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Center for the Study of the Presidency, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - China Institute in America, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Cold Spring Harbor Biological Laboratory, 1959-1975 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Conservation Foundation, 1959-1963 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Council on Chinese Affairs (Asian Society), 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Council on Foreign and International Studies, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Council of Higher Educational Institutions, 1958-1963 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Council of Higher Educational Institutions, 1964-1971 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Thomas A. Edison International Birthday Celebration, 1957-1979 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Education Committee to Halt Spread of Atomic Weapons, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Engineering Societies, 1955-1960 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Explorer Science Camp, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - General Electric - Lindon E. Saline, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Greater New York Council for Foreign Students, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Growth of American Families, 1955-1960 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - The Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1954-1960 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Oliver Wendell Holmes Association-The Paul AZS McGee Fund, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Mayo Foundation, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - National Defense Research Committee (NDRC), OSRD, Bronk Personal Papers, 1942-1947
    - National Defense Research Committee (NDRC), 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bronk, D.W., Personal Papers, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Bronk, D.W., Personal Papers, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - NDRC, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - NDRC, Bronk Personal Papers, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - NDRTC, Bronk Personal Papers, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Bronk Personal Papers, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Department of Commerce, Civil Aeronautics Administration, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Radio Corporation of America, U.S. Atlantic Fleet, NDRC, Office of Scientific Research and Development, 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - RCA Laboratories, 1946 May (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - OSRD, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - OSRD, NDRC, 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - NDRC, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - RCA, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Polaroid, RCA, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Polaroid, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - NDRC, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Bronk Personal Papers, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Bronk Personal Papers, 1942-1945 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Bronk Personal Papers, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - NDRC, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - NDRC, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - NDRC, 1942-1945 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - NDRC, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Office of the Quartermaster General Military Planning Division, Research and Development Branch, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Office of the Quartermaster General Military Planning Division, Research and Development Branch, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Office of the Quartermaster General Military Planning Division, Research and Development Branch, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - American Air Force - Office of Flying Safety, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1939-1943 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1939-1943 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - OSRD, NRC, 1942-1947
    - Office of Scientific Research and Development (OSRD), National Research Council (NRC), 1940-1946 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - OSRD, NRC, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Johnson Foundation, INRC, Flying Personnel Research Committee (FPRC), 1939-1945
    - Johnson Foundation, OSRD, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Johnson Foundation, OSRD, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Johnson Foundation, OSRD, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Johnson Foundation, OSRD, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Johnson Foundation, OSRD, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - NRC, Committee on Aviation Medicine, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - NRC, Committee on Aviation Medicine, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - National Research Council (NRC), Committee on Aviation Medicine (CAM), 1945 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - NRC, CAM, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - NRC, CAM, (Office of Research and Development (OSRD), 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - NRC, CAM, OSRD, 1942 May 11 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - NRC, CAM, OSRD, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - NRC, CAM, Flying Personnel Medical Officers, 1944-1945 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Flying Personnel Research Committee (FPRC), undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - FPRC, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - FPRC, 1937-1939 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - FPRC, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - FPRC, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - FPRC, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - FPRC, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - FPRC, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - FPRC, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - FPRC, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - FPRC, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Indexes of FPRC Reports and Papers, 1939-1943 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - FPRC, 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - FPRC, NRC, CAM, Royal Australian Air Force, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - NRC, CAM, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - NRC, CAM, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - NRC, CAM, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - NRC, CAM, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - NRC, CAM, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 32)